John Whitten

(he/him/his)

Full Stack Developer Designer | Educator | Creative

Portland, Oregon

johnwhitten.studio@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/johnwhittenstudio github.com/johnwhittenstudio johnwhittenstudio.com (615) 887.3367

About Me

Solution driven full stack developer, problem-solver, award-winning creative with a powerful set of skills and experiences. A champion of art, visual culture, and aesthetics.

Skills

Full stack development Functional programming Object-oriented programming HTML, CSS, JavaScript Node.js, jQuery, Webpack C# / .NET, React.js / Redux WordPress, PHP MySQL, NoSQL, Firebase UNIX command line, git and github RESTful API Dev & API Calls Debugging, DRY Code Test-Driven Development Pair Programming Concept Development Curriculum Development Instructional Design Adobe Creative Suite (15 years) Digital Photography Video + Audio Production 3D Modeling + Prototyping Excellent written & verbal skills Analytical + Detail-oriented Collaborative & Adaptive teammate

Education

Master of Fine Arts

University of Oregon, Eugene, OR major in interdisciplinary media

Bachelor of Fine Arts

Watkins College of Art, Nashville, TN major in studio fine art & design

Certifications

Web and Mobile Development, Epicodus, Portland, OR

- Completed (+1,000 hours) 10-month part-time program.
- Built 60+ projects using C#, JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS

Experience

Co-Founding Director & Web Designer Well Well Projects, Portland, OR 2020-present Carnation Contemporary, Portland, OR 2017-2021

2017 -**NOW**

2015 -

NOW

- Collaborated with a 6-person team to conceive, launch, and manage two cooperative art galleries with rotating monthly programming and community-focused events.
- Supported a 30-member base through website design & content management and exhibition documentation.
- Created captivating media content (web pages, videos, animations) for marketing and fundraising initiatives.

Full-Time Instructor of Digital Art & Video Oregon State University, Corvallis, OR & Ecampus

- Designed and facilitated (90+) term-long undergraduate on-campus + online courses geared for both majors and non-majors in digital art, video, animation, and design.
- Created compelling, accessible learning resources delivered through various platforms aimed to teach complex software skills and digital processes to beginner-level learners.
- Trained, advised, and equipped adjunct faculty with course content to instruct digital art courses.
- · Collaborated with Music faculty to orchestrate crossdisciplinary projects for music and digital art students + conceive, plan, and host community-engaged screenings.

Freelance Designer & Creative

Portland, OR / Eugene, OR / Nashville, TN

- Skilled artisan fulfilling multiple commissions of fine artworks,
- web design, layout design, videography, and photography. • Grant writer with over 12 projects funded by multiple orgs.
- Comfortable developing concepts, producing, and pitching completed work directly to the client.

Projects

2007 -

NOW

Thunderstruck

React portfolio website with interactive components for an artist residency.

Michelob Angelo's Pietàproom

React website with full CRUD capability for a fictitious tap room.

Interests











